#### Ken ZHANG

Tel: +61 415399812 E-mail: 819k.zhang@gmail.com anoncrazyer@protonmail.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Ken ZHANG, a software engineer and DevOps engineer with 5 years of experience, has a strong desire to self-learn and grow, has a great enthusiasm for coding and consistently codes every day, and is always delighted to help others.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Software Design, Bachelor of IT, University of Queensland

07 / 2019 -- Current

Course Highlights

- Python Programming 7 out of 7
- Data Structure 6 out of 7

Expected Graduation: 11 / 2021

- Web Design & Developing 6 out of 7
- Cyber Security 6 out of 7

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### **Tutor, University of Queensland**

02 / 2021 -- Current

- Teaching Computer Networking in the University course with 200+ participants, which was the largest number of students among all sessions in the university.
- Teaching Cyber Security Courses in UQ and helping professors select research students.

# DevOps, Program Peak Developing Team, China (Remote)

04 / 2017 -- 04 / 2018

- Providing 99.99 percent availability of CI/CD, monitoring, logging audit, load balancing, caching, and server high availability through open source tool chains that includes Zabbix, ELK, HaProxy, and Nginx. Log data transfer via HA Kafka was implemented.
- Initiated and established the emergency procedures for data loss and service unavailability.
- Helped the team deploy the Django web on K8s with my experience on the CNCF (Cloud Native) Ecology.

## **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

### Volunteer, KubeCon China, 2019

06 / 2019 -- 06 / 2019

Helped Ant Financial Group (pre-IPO) with testing Canary releases, Service Mesh, Distributed Transactions and Serverless before KubeCon workshops.

### Volunteer, KubeCon North America, 2019

11 / 2019 -- 11 / 2019

Interviewed with the CNCF TOC (Technical Oversight Committee) member about the study direction in computer science, K8s, and Cloud Native. Photography of presentations and events.

# PROJECT EXPERIENCE

## **Skyscraper - Overseas People Healthcare Assistance**

As the main developer, developed the core features of the application, built a full-stack web application project using ReactJS, LESS CSS, and Gin.

### **Clinical Informatics Systems Based On FHIR Workflows**

As the team leader, build an application developed for clients from CSIRO, using production level patient data, based on the FHIR API to process the radiological clinical workflows.

#### Automated deployed & scaling supported DevOps Pipeline

As the main DevOps Engineer, Built CI/CD integrated Jenkins pipeline, SonarQube code quality analysis, and Gitlab. Implemented Worker Node auto-scaling on K8s.

# **Programming Languages**

Experienced: Python, Java

Familiar: C++, C#, C, Golang, JavaScript, Clojure, Haskell

#### **Cloud Computing**

Experienced the operations of Linux (RHEL, CentOS, Ubuntu Server), and also well-versed in container orchestration tools like K8s. Knowledgeable in Python automation, database administration, and cloud computing platforms such as AWS services (EC2, S3) and Google Cloud Platform services (GCE).

### **Web Development**

Frontend Server: familiar with HTML5, CSS3 (incl. LESS), and JavaScript (incl. ReactJS, jQuery).

Frontend UI: familiar with Bootstrap 4, Bootstrap React, Ant Design (React)

Backend Server: experienced with Django (Python), Gin (Golang), LNMP (PHP).

Backend Database Systems: experienced with MySQL, MongoDB, and ElasticSearch.

## **Cyber Security**

Web Penetration Testing with Burp Suite, Nmap, Metasploit, Beef XSS. Understand the principles of various web security vulnerabilities.